# John Bedeir

# Senior DevOps Engineer

www.johnydev.com

Ocpenhagen, Denmark

#### SUMMARY

I am a skilled DevOps Engineer with 3+ years of hands-on experience and a total of 10 years of experience, an expert in Debian, RedHat, Unix & Windows OS with a strong development background.

My target is to master the DevSecOps culture, currently, I am focusing on applying GitOps, automate infrastructure to speed up the development and release process, Network, Security, and Cloud services.

My previous roles in the IT field started with providing level 1 and level 2 technical support as a System Administrator, troubleshooting, and maintenance of the technology infrastructure and systems for endpoint device management.

Then I became an IT Manager, which was more managerial level than technical, during this time I was preparing myself to be a DevOps engineer.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Senior DevOps Engineer

10/2021 - Present

PSQR (Copenhagen, Denmark)

- · Applying GitOps
- · Working with AWS, Digital Ocean & GCP
- Monitoring using Prometheus & Grafana
- · Using Terraform & Pulumi for IAC
- · Build, Test & Deploy using Jenkins.
- Project 1: Build testing environment for Ubuntu 18.04 & Ubuntu 20.04 using Ansible
- Project 2: Build Switch configuration using Terraform
- Project 3: Build an automated testing environment that works on both Debian & RedHat using Ansible
- Project 4: Build an automated testing environment that install Maria Galera | Java | Cassandra | Zookeeper and Elastic Search on both Debian & RedHat using Ansible Molecule
- Project 5: Jenkins Configuration as a Code.
- Project 6: Deploy and run Java application as a service on Windows EC2
- Project 7: Automate infrastructure to create Windows EC2 on AWS
- Project 8: Creating MSI Installer for Java application

# **DevOps Engineer** 01/2020 - 09/2021

Orange Business Services (Cairo, Egypt)

Orange Business Services is a French multinational telecommunications corporation.

- · Working in AGILE
- Project-1: Using Docker to containerize a web app
- Project-2: Build CI/CD automation with GitLab for web app
- Project-3: Manage all build and deploy tools, and oversee all deployments using Kubernetes, Ansible & Jenkins
- Project-4: Working with AWS using (EC2, IAM, Security Groups, etc.)
- Project-5: Django app & environment setup, Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins, AWS Deployment
- Project-6: PHP, Laravel environment setup, integrating Jenkins with Gitlab CI/CD, AWS Deployment.
- Project-7: Integrating Jenkins and Maven with Gitlab, setup Tomcat Server and use Docker, Ansible & Kubernetes in CI/CD Pipeline.
- Project-8: Setting up Kubernetes Cluster, EC2, Route53, S3 Bucket with Deploy and Service using Terraform & Ansible

IT Manager 09/2018 - 09/2019

Yaryor Technologies (Dubai, UAE)

- · Managing 5 employees
- Monitor performance of information technology systems to determine cost and productivity levels
- · Handle annual budget and ensure cost-effectiveness
- · Creating scripts to automate tasks

#### **Senior System Administrator**

03/2016 - 04/2018

Plus500 BG (Sofia, Bulgaria)

- Provide 24/7 Level 2 Support across all facilities.
- Ensure that helpdesk tickets are closed or escalated promptly.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Symantec endpoint console.
- Monitoring the Server room temperature via sensor.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned.

#### **Senior System Administrator**

01/2014 - 07/2015

Aroma Studios (Cairo, Egypt)

- Level 1 2 Support for all instances (on location, via phone & remotely)
- Install and configure Linux / Unix and perform system maintenance.
- Ensure assigned & pending tasks have been solved.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Kaspersky endpoint security management console.
- Check the Servers & Render-farm room temperature.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned

**System Administrator** 09/2011 - 12/2013

Arabcomed (Cairo, Egypt)

- · Level 1 Support on location, via phone or remotely,
- Ensure all the endpoint devices are working properly.
- Software & Hardware Troubleshooting.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Computer Science and Engineering (Cloud Computing)**

2019

Technical University (Sofia, Bulgaria) - Masters Degree

Computer Science 2011

Future Academy (Cairo, Egypt) - Bachelor's Degree

Volunteering Activity 2007

Enactus Organization (Cairo, Egypt) - Member of IT Committee

### SKILLS

.....

Windows OS / Linux / Unix Expert Kubernetes | HELM Advanced Docker / Vagrant **Jenkins** Advanced Expert Terraform **Bash Scripting** Expert Advanced **AWS** Advanced Version Control Expert Web Hosting Digital Ocean Intermediate Expert HTML5 / CSS3 Python | REST API Intermediate Expert Ansible Intermediate Expert **JavaScript** RedHat MS Azure Advanced Beginner